<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2079-09-01

 

Rheumatology Consult Note

Name: Mullins, Dolores U
MRN: 72841920
DOB: 06/06/02
Location: 78Q-47-4
Consult date: 09/01/79
Referring Physician: Gay Langley
Source of history: patient interview, medical records
Code status: Full

Reason for Consult: bilateral LE pain up to knees
HPI:
77 yo F w/h/o type I DM and HTN.  At the beginning of this year, she began to have intermittent    burning    pain of her feet and sometimes her lower legs/feet.  This pain typically occurred on one leg more than the other, without an overall predominance of one side.  In the past month, she has had continuous, bilateral    burning    pain that began in both feet.  Several weeks ago, her pain worsened considerably such that she was having difficulty shopping.  Around this time, the pain spread up her legs to above her knees.  She also noted having difficulty putting on shoes and was told by a friend that her feet were swollen (she is unable to see her feet due to blindness).  Her pain continued to worsen until the night prior to admission, when she was in her bathroom and found herself in such pain that she was unable to get up to leave the bathroom.  A friend found her after 8 hours and EMS was called.  In the ED, she was found to have BP elevated to 190, Cr elevated to 2.8, FSG down to 51, and R-sided hydronephrosis.  Labetolol/diltiazem were given for HTN with good response, IV hydration was given with subsequent decline in Cr, and Foley was placed with resolution of hydronephrosis on subsequent MRI.   

She has never had    burning    pain of the kind that she presented with prior to this year.  Of note, she has had    years    of tingling without numbness in her lower extremities bilaterally extending to above her knees.  She also notes numbness of the tips of her R 2nd-4th digits.  ROS positive for subjective decline in urine output and constipation (1 BM/2days).  She denies fever/chills/sweats, recent weight loss, fatigue, hypoglycemic episodes, cough/rhinorrhea/sore throat, SOB, orthpnea, CP, palpitations, abdominal pain, diarrhea, dysuria, polyuria/polydipsia.  

PMH: 
1) DM     type 1, since 2060, c/b retinopathy, nephropathy
2) HTN
3) Hypercholesterolemia
4) L internal capsule CVA 11/72
5) L eye legally blind 2/2 open angle glaucoma
6) thyroid nodule 7/78        benign    per patient
7) CRI     per HHMR, Cr 1.4 (4/78, 1/79) and 1.84 on 6/29/79

PSH:
1) bilateral cataracts
2) L eye    glaucoma    surgery
3) L eye    pressure shunt   
4) TAH at age 25




Admission Meds:
1) Labetalol 200 mg bid
2) HCTZ 25 mg qd
3) Lovastatin 20 mg qd
4) Enalapril 20 mg qd
5) Diltiazem 120 mg bid
6) ASA 81 mg qd
7) Novolin 10 U qam
8) NPH 70 U qam, 40 U qpm

Inpatient Meds: 
1) Ferrous sulphate 325 po tid
2) Enoxaparin 30 sc qd
3) Simvastatin 40 po qhs
4) Diltiazem SR 120 po bid
5) Labetolol 200 mg bid
6) Novolog SS ac, RISS qhs
7) NPH 70 U qam, 30 U qpm
8) Regular Insulin 10 U qam
9) Colchicine 0.6 mg qd (2 doses given)
10) Lumigan ou 1 drop qd
11) Prednisolone 1% 1 drop au bid
12) Colace 100 mg po bid
13) ASA 81 mg po qd
14) Oxycodone 10 mg po q6h prn
Gabapentin 100 mg tid     5 doses given before being discontinued

Allergies: NKDA

SH: Never smoked, does not currently drink ETOH, no h/o substance abuse, lives on the 2nd floor of an apartment (15 steps) and has neighbors who check in on her.  She is widowed with closest family being a cousin in Alaska.  She has been able to meet her needs of daily living independently. 

FH: Mother with fatal MI at 65, no family h/o rheumatic disease or cancer.  

PE: 
Tm 99.5, Tc 97.3, HR 51 (46-72), BP 126/50 (120-154/50-70), RR 18 (16-18), O2 sat 96% (94-98) RA
Gen     NAD when immobile, but great pain with minimal movement or contact with lower extremities
HEENT     2 mm pupils, EOM intact, no scleral icterus, oropharnyx nl, no gouty tophi on pinna
Neck     Supple, no lymphadenopathy, no JVD
CV     RRR, nl S1 S2, 2/6 SEM best heard in RUSB
Chest     Late inspiratory crackles at bases bilaterally
Abd     +BS, soft, NT, ND, liver edge above chostochondral margin, no palpable splenomegaly, no masses
Back     R CVA and flank tenderness
MSK     Heberdin and Bouchard   s nodes of PIPs/DIPs bilaterally, varus deformity of R 2nd-4th DIPs, no joint tenderness or reduced ROM of upper extremities; visible knee effusions bilaterally without erythema or warmth; exquisite tenderness to minimal motion or palpation of knees, tibio-talars, tarsals, and MTPs; no effusions palpable or visible in tibio-talars, tarsals, and MTPs
Ext     WWP, 1+ pedal edema bilaterally
Pulses     2+ DP bilaterally
Skin     no rashes, dry skin covering LEs greatest on medial aspect
Neuro    no focal upper extremity motor deficits, 5/5 finger grip




Labs:
Na 139, K 4.2, Cl 106, CO2 23, BUN 61, Cr 1.79 (1.69 yesterday), Glu 141, Ca 8.9, P 3.8, Mg 2.1
TP 6.9, Alb 3.0, Glob 3.9
ALT 14, AST 12, ALKP 76, TBILI 0.4
FE 12, TIBC 205, B12 303, Folate 12.7
HGBA1C 6.1
Uric acid 11.5
ESR 101, CRP 141.6
WBC 12.51 (N76 L14 M8 E2), Hct 28.8, Plt 398
Beta-hydroxybutyrate 0.41
UA sg 1.018, pH 5.0, protein 2+, 6 WBCs/hpf, 2+ bacteria, 1+ squames, no urine crystals

Studies:
TTE  (8/31/79, no prior studies)     Mild concentric LVH, LVEF 77%, impaired relaxation c/w diastolic dysfunction, mild left atrial enlargement, nl right atrium and ventricle, mild aortic stenosis, mild mitral regurgitation, estimated PASP 48.6, nl aortic root, no pericardial effusions
LE Doppler (8/31/79)     No evidence of proximal DVTs or calf DVTs bilaterally
Abdominal MRI (8/31/79)     Tiny cortical right renal hemorrhagic cysts, small hiatal hernia, right extrarenal pelvis without hydronephrosis or obstructing mass lesion
Renal U/S (8/30/79)     Mild right hydronephrosis with prominent extrarenal pelvis and multiple renal cysts, nl left kidney
CXR (8/29/79)     No evidence of pulmonary edema, PNX, or pleural effusion; aorta tortuous and partially calcified; degenerative changes of thoracic spine and left shoulder, cardiac silhouette prominent but wnl

Microbiology:
Blood cultures x2     Negative at 2 days
Urine cultures x2     5000 colonies mixed, 500 colonies probable lactobacilli

A/P: 77 yo F w/h/o DM and HTN who presented with several weeks of worsening bilateral LE burning pain exacerbated by movement and pressure.  She was found to have exquisitely tender joints up to and including her knees with visible synovial effusions of her knees bilaterally.  Aspiration of one of her knees revealed needle-shaped negatively birefringent crystals, diagnostic of gout.  This is consistent with her elevated uric acid and her elevated markers of inflammation (ESR/CRP).  Given that she has a long history of symptoms of LE diabetic neuropathy and that she has some diffuse soft tissue tenderness, she may also have some pain from diabetic neuropathy that may declare itself after her gout is treated.  However, her current inability to walk can be clearly attributed to gout.  

Recs:
- Solumedrol 40 mg bid IV, prednisone 40 mg qd starting tomorrow with 12-day outpatient taper (40 mg x 3 days, 30 mg x 3 days, 20 mg x 3 days, 10 mg x 3 days)
- Colchicine po 0.6 mg qd for 2 weeks, then 0.6 mg qod for 2 weeks
- Continue to hold HCTZ     discuss with PCP need to restart as outpatient as it is a risk factor for hyperuricemia
- F/u with rheumatology in 4 weeks for initiation of allopurinol (please arrange appointment w/ Dr. Yau)



Procedure: R knee aspiration
Patient was informed of the risks of bleeding and infection and gave consent. The medial aspect of the right knee was sterilized using iodine swabs x3, sterile gloves used in a one-handed sterile lateral approach. 1.5cc of 1% lidocaine was injected to raise a wheal inferior to the R patella. A 18G needle was inserted into the knee and approximately 20cc of opaque, yellow fluid was withdrawn. A slide was prepared and examined under the microscope by myself, Dr. Yau, and Dr. Woodard.  Abundant intracellular and extracellular needle-shapped negatively birefringent crystals were observed.  Synovial fluid sample was also submitted for culture, Gram stain, cell count, and crystal analysis.



__________________________________
Isaac Ito, MS4 x79975


Addendum:
Patient seen, records reviewed, case reviewed with medical student. Agree with excellent note above. Patient seen with Dr. Woodard.




______________________
Unknown Yau, MD
Rheumatology fellow




]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2079-09-01" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P1" start="64" end="82" text="Mullins, Dolores U" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P2" start="88" end="96" text="72841920" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="102" end="110" text="06/06/02" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P5" start="144" end="152" text="09/01/79" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P6" start="174" end="185" text="Gay Langley" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<AGE id="P7" start="314" end="316" text="77" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P8" start="2147" end="2151" text="2060" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P9" start="2239" end="2244" text="11/72" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P10" start="2310" end="2314" text="7/78" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P11" start="2359" end="2363" text="HHMR" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<DATE id="P12" start="2373" end="2377" text="4/78" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P13" start="2379" end="2383" text="1/79" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P14" start="2397" end="2404" text="6/29/79" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P15" start="2510" end="2512" text="25" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P16" start="3409" end="3415" text="Alaska" TYPE="STATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P17" start="3515" end="3517" text="65" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P18" start="5160" end="5167" text="8/31/79" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P19" start="5453" end="5460" text="8/31/79" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P20" start="5535" end="5542" text="8/31/79" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P21" start="5699" end="5706" text="8/30/79" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P22" start="5817" end="5824" text="8/29/79" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P23" start="6163" end="6165" text="77" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P24" start="7401" end="7404" text="Yau" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P25" start="7903" end="7906" text="Yau" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P26" start="7916" end="7923" text="Woodard" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P27" start="8169" end="8178" text="Isaac Ito" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<CONTACT id="P28" start="8185" end="8190" text="79975" TYPE="PHONE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P29" start="8326" end="8333" text="Woodard" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P30" start="8362" end="8373" text="Unknown Yau" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>